Patent medicine almanacs
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
Patent medicine almanacs
1843-1966
Pam Coll 3
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
5
(10 boxes and 3 albums)
The collection contains almanacs issued annually by American and a few Canadian companies to promote the sale of their proprietary remedies. Of special note is a complete collection of Hostetter's Almanac from 1867 through 1910.
Abell, Truman, 1779-1853
Brown, O. Phelps (Oliver Phelps)
Daboll, Nathan, 1782-1863
Fitch, Samuel Sheldon, 1801-1876
Moffat, William Brinckerhoff, 1818-1862
White, A. J.
A.L. Scovill & Co
Dr. J.C. Ayer & Co
Barker, Moore & Mein Medicine Co
Calumet Herb Co
Centaur Company
Chattanooga Medicine Company
W.H. Comstock Co
Perry Davis & Son
P.H. Drake & Co
B.A. Fahnestock & Co
Seth W. Fowle & Sons
C.C. Green (Firm)
Illinois Herb Co
D. Jayne and Son
R.H. McDonald & Co
Dr. Miles Medical Co
Miles Laboratories
Merchant's Gargling Oil Company
J. B. Ross & Co
Peruna Drug Mfg. Co
University Publishing Company
J. H. Schenck & Son
Jeremiah Curtis & Sons
John I. Brown & Sons
Lyman Brown (Firm)
National Association of Retail Druggists (U.S.)
J.H. Zeilin & Co
Wells, Richardson & Co
Graefenberg Company
Foster, Milburn & Co
Dr. Kilmer & Co
H.H. Warner & Co
Roback, C. W. (Charles W.)
Dr. Radway & Co
Herrick & Co
Hostetter & Smith
Indiana Botanic Gardens
Louden & Co
Rumford Chemical Works
A.B. & D. Sands (Firm)
W.T. Rawleigh Company
John F. Henry, Curran & Co
Victor Remedies Co
Dr. A.W. Chase Medicine Co
Saxton & Miles
Piso Company
World's Dispensary Medical Association
Arrangement
Almanacs in the first series have been arranged by short title. Titles of almanacs often vary from year to year. Depending on the consistency, titles may fall in more than one place with cross references. Sometimes variant titles have been grouped. Pamphlets in the second series have been retained in the order established by the collector.
Scope and Contents
The almanacs in this collection were issued annually by American and a few Canadian companies to promote the sale of their proprietary remedies. The remedies were secret rather than actually patented, and exaggerated claims were made for what they could cure. Almanacs were distributed free to customers by drug stores. Typically the back cover of the almanac carried an advertisement for an individual pharmacy. Often the almanacs had a hole at the top left, through which a string was tied so that they could be hung on a nail on the wall. Two almanacs are in miniature format.
Custodial History
Some almanacs were transferred from Sterling Memorial Library in the 1940s. Many others were donated by William H. Helfand. The Supplement contains additional almanacs and a few other patent medicine pamphlets collected by Lloyd Moore and donated by his daughter Kathi Moore Sherman in 2018.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Related Materials
Related collections at the Medical Historical Library include the Sheet music collection on medical themes (Pam Coll 5), the Medical trade card collection (Pam Coll 6), and the William Helfand collection of medical ephemera (Pam Coll 8).
Separated Materials
Some patent medicine almanacs in the Medical Historical Library have been cataloged separately on Orbis. For titles in this collection, the existence of other issues has been noted. Other titles not represented include Hop Bitters Almanac for 1877, Brayley's Family Medical Almanac 1883, Kickapoo Almanac, 1893, and "Rough on Rats" 1884 Almanac.
Patent medicines -- Canada; Patent medicines -- United States; Almanacs, American; Almanacs, Canadian; Medicine, Popular; Commercial catalogs; Advertisements -- Medicines, Patent, proprietary, etc.; Almanacs; Miniature books; Agricultural and family almanac; Almanac and guide to health; Almanac and weather forecasts; Almanach francais d'Ayer; August flower and German syrup alamanac; Ayer's American almanac; Ayer's Amerikanischer Almanach; Ayer's Deutscher Almanach; Ayer's Svenska Almanacka; Barker's illustrated almanac; Benefactor: an almanac; Brandreth annual calendar; Brant's family almanac; Bristol's free almanac; Bucklen's almanac; Burdock Blood Bitters almanac; C.W. Roback's astrological almanac; Centaur almanac; Centennial calendar or Simmons Liver Regulator almanac; Christie's family almanac; Clark's Anti-Bilious Compound almanac; Clark's Cleveland almanac; The Diamond Dye almanac and household guide; Doan's Directory of the United States; Dr. A.W. Chase's calendar-almanac; Dr. Browder's family almanac; Dr. C.W. Roback's family pictorial almanac; Dr. Jayne's medical almanac and guide to health; Dr. McLean's medical almanac; Dr. Miles new weather almanac and hand book of valuable information; Dr. Morse's Indian root pills almanac; Dr. O. Phelps Brown's Shakespearian almanac; Dr. Roback's medical almanac; Dr. S.S. Fitch's almanac; Dr. Wistar's free almanac; Epilepsy (fits) and St. Vitus dance (chorea); Everybody's almanac and family receipt book; Excelsior almanac; Fahnestock & Co.'s free almanac; The Family health almanac; Family medical almanac; Family almanac, and Franklin calendar; Farmer's and mechanic's almanac; Farmers and mechanics almanac and family recipe book; Farmers' almanac an ephemerides of the motion of the sun and moon, the rising and the setting of the sun, and the rising, setting, and southing of the moon; Farmer's and mechanic's almanac; Frederick almanac; Free almanac for the world and advertiser; George Coster & Co's family almanac and medical repository; Graefenberg Company's almanac; Green's atlas and diary almanac; Grier's almanac for the states of South Carolina, Georgia, Floirda, Alabama, Mississippi, Tennessee, Louisiana and Texas; Hazeltine's pocket book almanac; The Health almanac; Health almanac, and guide to invalids; Healthway products almanac; The Herbalist almanac; National calendar or Herrick's almanac; The Home almanac; Hoofland's almanac; Horsford almanac and cook book; Hostetter's United States almanac; Hostetter's illustrated United States almanac; The Household almanac; Hufeland's Kalender und Familien Recept Buch; Illinois Herb Co. Almanac; The Illustrated family medical almanac; Illustrated family recipe and medical almanac; Jayne's medical almanac and guide to health; Jayne's medizinischer Calender und Gesundheits-Wegweiser; Kodol almanac and 200 year calendar; Ladies birthday almanac; The Magnetic almanac...for the use of everybody; Merchant's Gargling Oil almanac; Miles new weather almanac; Moffat's agricultural almanac; Morning, noon, and night; Mrs. Winsow's Domestic Receipt Book; Munyon's almanac; N.A.R.D. almanac; The New York almanac; The New-England almanac, and farmer's friend; The New-England farmer's almanac; Northrup & Lyman Co's almanac and guide to health; Pain-Killer almanac and family receipt book; Pierce's memorandum and account book; The People's almanac; The People's illustrated almanac; Peruna almanac; PIso's pocket book almanac; Poor Richard Lactopeptine almanack; Dr. Radway's almanac; Rawleigh's almanac; Rawleigh's good health guide almanac cook book; Der Recept-Kalender; Rescue of Tula almanac; Rosadalis almanac; Rush's almanac and guide to health; Scheetz's illustrated almanac; Schenck's almanac for the million; Schenk's Almanach; Seven barks almanac; Shaker almanac; The Story of the Shakers and some of their favorite cooking recipes; Swamp-root almanac; Trail blazer's almanac and pioneer guide book; The Treasure chest almanac; Tucker & Co's national almanac; University almanac and business book; Vennor's weather almanac; The Vermont state almanac; Veterans of the war whom all should assist offer their almanac; Vinegar bitters almanac; Warner's safe cure almanac; Watkin's almanac home doctor and cook book; Wright's family almanac; Wright's pictorial family almanac; Helfand, William H.; Moore, Lloyd, 1916-2004
- Original collection, 1843-1966; Series I
  - A. L. Scovill & Co.'s Farmers & Mechanics Almanac, 1862, 1864, 1867, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Published by A. L. Scovill & Co., Cincinnati, Ohio. See also an 1856 almanac titled Farmer's and Mechanic's Almanac and published by A. L. Scovill, Cincinnati.
  - A. L. Scovill & Co.'s Farmers & Mechanics Almanac, 1870, 1871 (2 variants) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    See later almanac under John F. Henry & Curran Co...Farmer's and Mechanic's Almanac
  - Almanac and Weather Forecasts, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Published by the Alonzo Bliss Co., Washington, D.C.
  - August Flower and German Syrup Almanac, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Published by G. G. Green, Woodbury, N.J. Another almanac under the same title for 1890 has been cataloged separately. An issue of Green's Census and Diary Almanac has also been cataloged separately.
  - [Ayer] Almanach Français d'Ayer, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Published by Dr. J. C. Ayer & Co., Lowell, Mass.
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1853, 1854, 1861, 1856, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1859, 1860, 1861, 1862, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1864, 1865, 1866, 1867, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1869, 1870, 1871, 1872, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1874, 1875, 1876, 1877, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1879, 1880, 1881, 1882, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1884, 1885, 1886, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1888, 1889, 1890, 1891, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Another 1889 almanac, titled Ayer's almanac for 1889, has been cataloged separately.
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1893, 1894, 1895, 1896, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1898, 1899, 1902, 1904, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1907, 1909, 1911, 1912, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ayer's American Almanac, 1914, 1915, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ayer's American Almanac Canadian Edition, 1902, 1911, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Ayer's American Almanac New England Edition, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ayer's Amerikanischer Almanach, 1856, 1867 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Ayer's Deutscher Almanach, 1881, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ayer's Svenska Almanacka, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Ayer's 20th Century Almanac, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - B. A. Fahnestock & Co.'s Free Almanac, 1851, 1852, 1853, 1856 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Published by B. A. Fahnestock & Co., Pittsburgh. Variant titles are R. A. Fahnestock & Co.'s Almanac, and B. A. Fahnestock, Hull & Co.'s Free Almanac.
  - The Benefactor, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    By George E. Stanton & Co., Sing Sing, N.Y.
  - Brandreth's Annual Calendar/ Dr. Brandreth's Almanac, 1860, 1869, 1875, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Published by Dr. B. Brandreth, New York, N.Y.
  - Brandreth Annual Calendar, 1880, 1881, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Brant's Family Almanac, 1852, 1853, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Almanac for 1852 published by Wallace & Co., New York, N.Y. Almanac for 1854 published by M. T. Wallace & Co., Brooklyn, N.Y.
  - Bristol's Free Almanac, 1843, 1844, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Publication information unclear. Advertises Bristol's Sarsaparilla manufactured by C. C. Bristol, Chemist & Druggist, Buffalo, N.Y., William Burger, General Agent, New York, N.Y.
  - Bucklen's Almanac, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Published by H.E. Bucklen & Co., Chicago.
  - Burdock Blood Bitters Almanac and Key to Health, 1884, 1885, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Published by Foster, Milburn & Co., Buffalo, N.Y. See also Series 2, Volume 3.
  - Burdock Blood Bitters Almanac and Key to Health, 1887, 1888, 1889, 1890, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    The 1893 almanac was published by T. Milburn & Co., Toronto, Canada.
  - C. W. Roback's Astrological Almanac/ Dr. C. W. Roback's Family Pictorial Almanac/ Dr. Roback's Medical Almanac, 1851, 1855, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    1851 almanac published by C. W. Roback, Philadelphia. 1856 Almanac published by C. W. Roback, Cincinnati.
  - Centaur Almanac, 1873, 1874, 1875, 1876, 1886 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Published by J. B. Ross & Co., New York. The 1886 almanac was titled Centaur Almanac and Cookbook.
  - Centennial Calendar and Simmons Liver Regulator, 1876, 1879, 1880 (2 copies), 1882, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Published by J. H. Zeitlin & Co., Philadelphia. The 1876 almanac was titled Centennial Record and Simmons Liver Regulator.
  - Christie's Family Almanac, 1854, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Published by D. C. Morehead, M.D., New York, N.Y.
  - Clarks' Cleveland Almanac/ Clarks' Anti-Bilious Compound Almanac, 1875, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    1875 almanac published by R.C. & C.S. Clark, Operative Chemists, Cleveland, Ohio.
  - The Diamond Dye Almanac, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Published by Wells, Richardson & Co., Burlington, Vermont.
  - Dr. A. W. Chase's Calendar Almanac, 1923, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Published by Dr. S. W. Chase Medicine Co., Toronto, Canada.
  - Dr. Browder's Family Almanac, 1847 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Published by William A. Egery, Boston.
  - Dr. D. Jayne's Medical Almanac and Guide to Health, 1880, 1885 (2 variants), 1898 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Published by Dr. D. Jayne & Son, Philadelphia. The 1880 almanac and one of the variant 1885 almanacs are titled Dr. Jayne's Medical Almanac. See also under Jayne's and in Series 2, Volume 3.
  - Dr. D. Jayne's Medical Almanac and Guide to Health, 1908, 1910, 1924, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Dr. McLean's Medical Almanac, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Published by Dr. J. H. McLean Medicine Co., St. Louis, Missouri.
  - Dr. Miles New Weather Almanac, 1911, 1918, 1931, 1932, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Published by Dr. Miles Medical Co., Elkhart, Indiana.
  - Dr. Miles New Weather Almanac, 1935, 1938, 1939, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Dr. Morse's Indian Root Pills Almanac, 1898, 1902, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Published by the W. H. Comstock Company, Limited, Morristown, St. Lawrence County, New York and Brockville, Ontario, Canada.
  - Dr. O. Phelps Brown's Shakespearian Almanac, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Published by J. Gibson Brown, Jersey City, N.J.
  - Dr. Radway's Almanac/ Radway's R.R.R. Almanac, 1862, 1867, 1869, 1872, 1873 (2 versions), 1875 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Published by Dr. Radway & Co., New York, N.Y. Titles vary. They include Dr. Radway's Constitutional Almanac (1862), Dr. Radway's Almanac (1867), R.R.R. Dr. Radway's Almanac (1869, 1872), Radway's R.R.R. Almanac and Guide to Health (1873, 1875). R.R.R. stands for Radway's Ready Relief.
  - Dr. S. S. Fitch's Almanac/ Dr. S. S. Fitch's Family Almanac, 1854, 1860, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Published by S. S. Fitch & Co., New York, N.Y.
  - Dr. Wistar's Free Almanac, 1846, 1847, 1848, 1849, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Published by Seth W. Fowle, Boston.
  - Everybody's Almanac and Family Receipt Book, 1856, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Published by C. M. Jackson, M.D., Philadelphia.
  - Excelsior Almanac, 1870 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Published by Dr. [Benjamin] Brandreth, New York. See also Brandreth Annual Calendar. Another 1870 almanac under the same title has been cataloged separately.
  - Family Almanac, and Franklin Calendar, 1849 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Published by E. Darrow, Rochester, N.Y.
  - The Family Almanac and Guide to Health, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    By S[amuel]. S[heldon]. Fitch, New York, N.Y. See also Dr. S. S. Fitch's Almanac.
  - Family Health Almanac, 1876 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Published by the Office of the Health Reformer, Battle Creek, Michigan.
  - Family Medical Almanac, 1845 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Published by Comstock & Co., New York, N. Y.
  - Farmers' Almanac, 1872, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    "By Samuel Hart Wright, M.D., Penn Yan, Yates County, N.Y." Published by Pinchot, Bruen & Hobart, Wholesale Druggists, New York, N.Y.
  - Farmers' Almanac, 1885, 1886, 1887, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    By R. W. Robinson & Son, Druggists, New York, N.Y.
  - Farmers' Almanac, 1889, 1890, 1891, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Farmers' Almanac, 1893, 1894, 1895, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Farmers' Almanac, 1897, 1898, 1899, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Farmers' Almanac, 1901, 1902, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Farmers' Almanac, 1904, 1905, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Farmer's and Mechanic's Almanac, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Published by A. L. Scovill, Cincinnati, Ohio. See also A. L. Scovill & Co.'s Farmers and Mechanics Almanac.
  - Farmer's and Mechanic's Almanac, 1858 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Published by Bolles, Smith & Co., Chicago.
  - Farmers' and Mechanics' Almanac, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Published by C. G. Clark & Co., Wholesale Druggists, New Haven, Conn.
  - Farmer's and Mechanics Almanac, 1852, 1853, 1854, 1855, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Published by William B. Moffat, New York, N.Y. See also under Moffat's.
  - The Frederick Almanac, 1905, 1907, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Published by Victor Remedies Co., Frederick City, Maryland. The Frederick Almanac for the Year of Our Lord 1908 has been cataloged separately.
  - Free Almanac for the World, 1849, 1853 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - The Gargling Oil Company's National Almanac, 1862, 1863, 1868 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Published by Merchant's Gargling Oil Co., successors to Geo. W. Merchant, Lockport, N.Y. See also Merchant's Gargling Oil Almanac and Series 2, Volume 3.
  - George Coster & Co's Family Almanac and Medical Repository, 1873, 1874, 1875, 1876 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Published by George Coster & Co., Mobile, Alabama. Alternate titles include Coster & Sprague's Family Almanac and Medical Repository, and Geo. Coster & Co's Family Almanac and Medical Repository.
  - Graefenberg Almanac, 1859, 1860, 1861, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Published by the Graefenberg Company, New York, N.Y. Alternate titles include simply Almanac.
  - Green's Pictorial Almanac, 1879, 1880, 1881 (2 versions), 1882 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Published by G. G. Green, Woodbury, N.J. Variant titles include Green's Atlas and Diary Almanac, Green's Census and Diary Almanac and Green's Diary Almanac. See also Series 2, Volume 3.
  - Grier's Almanac, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    "Copyright and printed by J. W. Burke & Co., Macon, Ga...presented by Howard & Willet, Wholesale Druggists, Augusta, Ga."
  - Hazeltine's Pocket Book Almanac, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Miniature almanac 5 x 3 cm. Published by E. T. Hazeltine, Warren, Pa.
  - Health Almanac and Guide to Invalids, 1851, 1852, 1853 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Published by Samuel Sheldon Fitch, New York, N.Y. See also Dr. S. S. Fitch's Almanac. Additional issues of this title have been cataloged separately.
  - Healthway Products Almanac, 1950, 1960, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    By the Illinois Herb Company, Chicago. Uses an Indian motif.
  - The Herbalist Almanac, 1933, 1934, 1936, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Published by the Calumet Herb Co., South Holland, Ill. Indian motif.
  - The Herbalist Almanac, 1939, 1940, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Herrick's Almanac, 1878 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    By L. W. Warner & Co., New York, N.Y.
  - The Home Almanac, 1858 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Published by Seth W. Fowle & Co., Boston.
  - Hoofland's Almanac, 1878 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Published by Johnston, Holloway & Co., Philadelphia.
  - [Hoofland] Hufeland's Kalender, 1876, 1879 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Horsford Almanac and Cook Book, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Published by the Rumford Chemical Works, Providence, R.I.
  - Hostetter's United States Almanac, 1864, 1869, 1871, 1873 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Published by Hostetter & Smith, Pittsburgh, Pa. Variant title is Hostetter's Illustrated United States Almanac. See Series 2, Volumes 1 and 2 for a complete set of Hostetter's Alamabac, 1867-1910.
  - Hostetter's Illustrated United States Almanac, 1877, 1878, 1879, 1885, 1886 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Published by Hostetter & Smith, Pittsburgh, Pa. (1877, 1878, 1879, 1885) or Hostetter and Co., Pittsburgh, Pa. (1886).
  - Hostetter's Illustrated United States Almanac, 1888, 1897, 1906, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Hostetters illustrerte forenede staters Almanak, 1890, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Household Almanac, 1887 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Published by Henry, Johnson, & Lord, Burlington, Vt.
  - Illinois Herb Co. Almanac, 1937, 1938, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Published by the Illinois Herb Co., Chicago. See also Healthway Products.
  - Illinois Herb Co. Healthway Products Almanac, 1937, 1938, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Published by the Illinois Herb Co., Chicago. See also Healthway Products Almanac and Illinois Herb Co. Healthway Products Almanac. Indian motif.
  - The Illustrated Family Recipe and Medical Almanac, 1850, 1853, 1854, 1857 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Published by A. B. & D. Sands, Wholesale Druggists, New York, N.Y.
  - Jayne's Medical Almanac, and Guide to Health, 1848, 1850, 1851, 1852 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Published by Dr. D. Jayne, Philadelphia.
  - Jayne's Medical Almanac and Guide to Health, 1853, 1855, 1858, 1859 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Beginning with the 1858 almanac, the publisher became Dr. D. Jayne & Son, Philadelphia.
  - Jayne's Medical Almanac and Guide to Health, 1860, 1868, 1869, 1870, 1871 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Jayne's Medical Almanac and Guide to Health, 1935, 1937, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    For intervening years, see Dr. D. Jayne's Medical Almanac and Guide to Health.
  - [Jayne's] Dr. Jayne's Arzenei-Kalender, und Gesundsheit-Wegweiser/ Jayne's Medizinischer Calender und Gesundheits-Wegweiser, 1849, 1859, 1872 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - [Jayne's] Jahne's Medizinischer Calender und Gesundheits Weg-Weiser, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - John F. Henry, Curran & Co...Farmer's & Mechanic's Almanac, 1875, 1877 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Published by John F. Henry, Curran & Co. successors to A. L. Scovill & Co., New York, N.Y. See earlier almanacs under A. L. Scovill.
  - Kodol Almanac, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Published by E. C. Dewitt & Co., Chicago.
  - The Ladies Birthday Almanac, 1910, 1911, 1913, 1914, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Published by the Chattanooga Medicine Co., Chattanooga, Tenn. Indian motif.
  - The Ladies Birthday Almanac, 1921, 1928, 1939, 1940, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - The Ladies Birthday Almanac, 1944, 1946, 1952, 1956, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Magnetic Almanac, 1866, 1867, 1868 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Published by D. Ransom & Co., Buffalo, N.Y.
  - Merchant's Gargling Oil Almanac, 1875, 1876, 1878, 1879, 1880 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Published by Merchant's Gargling Oil Company, Lockport, N.Y. Title of 1875 almanac is Merchant's Gargling Oil National Almanac.
  - Merchant's Gargling Oil Almanac, 1881, 1884, 1886 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Moffat's Agricultural Almanac [and related titles], 1845, 1846, 1847, 1848, 1850, 1851 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Published by Dr. William B. Moffat, New York, N.Y. Title varies greatly. The titles are Moffat's Agricultural Almanac (1845), Moffat's Medical and Agricultural Almanack (1846), Moffat's...Agricultural and Family Almanack (1847), Agricultural and Family Almanac (1848, 1850), and The Family Almanac (1851).
  - Morning Noon and Night, 1870, 1872 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Published by P. H. Drake & Co., New York, N.Y.
  - Munyon's Almanac, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Published by the Munyon Remedy Co., Philadelphia.
  - N.A.R.D. Almanac, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Published by the National Association of Retail Druggists.
  - National Calendar or Herrick's Almanac, 1862, 1863, 1864, 1866, 1867 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Published by Dr. Herrick & Brother, Practical Chemists, Albany, N.Y. See also Series 2, Volume 3.
  - National Calendar or Herrick's Almanac, 1869, 1870, 1871, 1872, 1873 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    1872 almanac and after published by L. W. Warner & Co., New York, N.Y.
  - National Calendar or Herrick's Almanac, 1874, 1875 (2 versions), 1876, 1877, 1882 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Almanacs for 1876, 1877, and 1882 are titled Herrick's Almanac.